<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Po-Chien Shen 沈伯鍵 | DLit-Hub</title>
    <link>http://localhost:50624/author/po-chien-shen-%E6%B2%88%E4%BC%AF%E9%8D%B5/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:50624/author/po-chien-shen-%E6%B2%88%E4%BC%AF%E9%8D%B5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Po-Chien Shen 沈伯鍵</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:50624/author/po-chien-shen-%E6%B2%88%E4%BC%AF%E9%8D%B5/avatar_hu508877709439512294.png</url>
      <title>Po-Chien Shen 沈伯鍵</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50624/author/po-chien-shen-%E6%B2%88%E4%BC%AF%E9%8D%B5/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Po-Chien Shen 沈伯鍵</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50624/author/po-chien-shen-%E6%B2%88%E4%BC%AF%E9%8D%B5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50624/author/po-chien-shen-%E6%B2%88%E4%BC%AF%E9%8D%B5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;我是放射腫瘤科醫師，在臨床工作之餘，專注研究透過資料科學分析臨床數據，推動放射治療的個人化發展。我的研究核心在於結合影像組學，探討如何預測患者的放療副作用及預後。期望在現行治療指引的基礎上，進一步針對個別患者的風險，量身優化放射治療的劑量或照野，提升治療的精準性與效果。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>新 Preprint 發表於 biorxiv</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50624/event/driveromics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50624/event/driveromics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DriverOmicsNet-An Integrated Graph Convolutional Network for Multi-Omics Exploration of Cancer Driver Genes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Cancer is a complex and heterogeneous group of diseases driven by genetic mutations and molecular changes. Identifying and characterizing cancer driver genes (CDgs) is crucial for understanding cancer biology and guiding precision oncology. Integrating multi-omics data can reveal the intricate molecular interactions underlying cancer progression and treatment responses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We developed a graph convolutional network (GCN) framework, DriverOmicsNet, that integrates multi-omics data using STRING protein-protein interaction (PPI) networks and correlation-based weighted correlation network analysis (WGCNA). We applied this framework to 15 cancer types, analyzing 5555 tumor samples to predict cancer-related features such as homologous recombination deficiency (HRD), cancer stemness, immune clusters, tumor stage, and survival outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Findings: DriverOmicsNet demonstrated superior predictive accuracy and model performance metrics across all target labels when compared with GCN models based on STRING network alone. Gene expression emerged as the most significant feature, reflecting the dynamic and functional state of cancer cells. The combined use of STRING PPI and WGCNA networks enhanced the identification of key driver genes and their interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interpretation: Our study highlights the effectiveness of using GCNs to integrate multi-omics data for precision oncology. The integration of STRING PPI and WGCNA networks provides a comprehensive framework that improves predictive power and facilitates the understanding of cancer biology, paving the way for more tailored treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
